<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Al Shakib</title><link>https://alshakib.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Al Shakib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:42:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alshakib.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a Custom Image of Fedora Cloud for Google Compute Engine</title><link>https://alshakib.github.io/blog/create-a-custom-image-of-fedora-cloud-for-gcp-09-09-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:42:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://alshakib.github.io/blog/create-a-custom-image-of-fedora-cloud-for-gcp-09-09-2020/</guid><description>Introduction Fedora has been my primary operating system for many years. Recently I was doing some computation in the Google Compute Engine. In case you don’t know about Google Compute Engine, you can start from here . I’ve been disappointed that there is no prebuilt image of Fedora in Google Compute Engine. But they provide a way to create custom images from source disks, images, snapshots, or images stored in Cloud Storage.</description></item><item><title>Let Me Introduce Tasker</title><link>https://alshakib.github.io/blog/let_me_introduce_tasker-18-07-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 22:21:38 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://alshakib.github.io/blog/let_me_introduce_tasker-18-07-2020/</guid><description>Introduction In most applications, you’ll need a way to update its data. If you’re not careful, your application will do almost all of its work on the main event thread because this thread runs your event methods. If you just drop your heavy task code into the main event thread, then the main event thread will be busy with the heavy task, instead of rushing off to look for any events from the screen or other applications.</description></item><item><title>A Story of Creating Drawable From Text</title><link>https://alshakib.github.io/blog/a-story-of-creating-drawable-from-text-14-06-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 21:37:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://alshakib.github.io/blog/a-story-of-creating-drawable-from-text-14-06-2020/</guid><description>Introduction Today I’m going to release the initial version of Android DText Library. It converts string text to a drawable image. You can find the GitHub repository here .
I created DText as a part of my other personal (Yet unfinished) project. What I needed was to create an icon (or you can say avatar) with the first character of the title. Like Contacts app from Google. As I’m a lazy human being, I was looking for a simple solution.</description></item><item><title>Hello World (Blog)!</title><link>https://alshakib.github.io/blog/hello-world-23-04-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alshakib.github.io/blog/hello-world-23-04-2020/</guid><description> “The secret to getting ahead is getting started.”
― Mark Twain</description></item></channel></rss>